Guide to the Allegheny County, Pa. Jail Records (Court Dockets), 1863-1932 AIS.1975.08
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allegheny County, Pa. Jail Records (Court Dockets)
1863-1932
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1975.08
98 microfilm_reels (98 volumes)
Collection contains ledgers documenting jail records and court dockets for individuals incarcerated in the Allegheny County Jail between 1863-1932.
Scope and Content Notes
Daily Register (Daily Record) of prisoners received, 1893-1925; Vagrants Received and Discharged, 1886-1925; Court Dockets, 1864-1926; Index to Court Dockets, 1901-1925; Summary Docket (Summary Convictions; Summary Register), 1863-1929; Summary of Convictions, 1907-1926; Courts: Received and Discharged, 1886- 1922; Daily Disposition Record, 1906-1925; Alphabetical List of Prisoners' and Attorneys' Names, 1914-1921; Docket of United States Prisoners, 1899-1926; Convict Description Docket, 1920-1932; Discharge Description Docket, 1873-1928; Quarterly Report of All Persons Committed to Allegheny County Prison, 1909-1912; Ledger, 1900-1921; Journal (Day Book), 1902-1924; Cash book, 1923-1927.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the Allegheny County Jail, August 12, 1975.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
History
In 1817 the county commissioners were authorized by the state to erect a jail in Pittsburgh at the corner of 4th Avenue and Jail Alley. In 1836 a new Allegheny County Jail and Courthouse was erected on Grant Street. When the courthouse was destroyed by fire in 1882, the jail was razed and the present structure was built on Ross Street in 1886. The Allegheny County Jail has always been under the control of the county commissioners.
Previous Citation
Allegheny County, Pa. Jail Records (Court Dockets), 1863-1932, AIS.1975.08, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Government; Allegheny County (Pa.); Court records -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Jails -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail (Pittsburgh, Pa.) -- Records and correspondence
- Daily Register (Daily Record), 1893-1925; I.; 12 Volumes
  Scope and Content Notes
  Daily register of prisoners received. Contains: name; residence; age; sex; color; nationality; occupation; marital status; literacy; to be held for court or as a vagrant; charge.
  - Volume 1, Jul 1, 1892-Mar 29, 1893 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 1)
  - Volume 2, Apr 1, 1893-May 31, 1894 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 2)
  - Volume 3, Jun 1, 1894-Nov 30, 1896 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 3)
  - Volume 4, Dec 1, 1896-Jul 31, 1899 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 4)
  - Volume 5, Aug 1, 1899-May 19, 1901 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 5)
  - Volume 6, May 20, 1901-Oct 31, 1902 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 6)
  - Volume 7, Nov 1, 1902-Mar 31, 1904 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 7)
  - Volume 8, Jun 21, 1907-Nov 30, 1909 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 8)
  - Volume 9, Nov 1, 1914-Mar 31, 1917 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 9)
  - Volume 10, Apr 1, 1917-Oct 31, 1919 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 10)
  - Volume 11, Nov 1, 1919-Apr 30, 1923 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 11)
  - Volume 12, May 1, 1923-May 31, 1925 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 12)
- Vagrants Received and Discharged, 1886-1925; II.; 13 Volumes
  Contains: date received; name and date scheduled for release; name and date of release.
  - Volume 1, Sep 1, 1886-Nov 25, 1890 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 13)
  - Volume 2, Jan 1, 1895-May 31, 1898 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 14)
  - Volume 3, Jun 1, 1898-Jan 31, 1901 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 15)
  - Volume 4, Feb 1, 1901-Mar 31, 1903 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 16)
  - Volume 5, Apr 1, 1903-Jan 30, 1905 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 17)
  - Volume 6, Feb 1, 1905-Sep 30, 1906 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 18)
  - Volume 7, Oct 1, 1906-Jun 30, 1908 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 19)
  - Volume 8, May 1, 1910-Apr 30, 1912 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 20)
  - Volume 9, May 1, 1912-Jan 31, 1914 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 21)
  - Volume 10, Jan 1, 1916-Feb 19, 1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 22)
  - Volume 11, Feb 20, 1918-Jul 31, 1921 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 23)
  - Volume 12, Aug 1, 1921-Dec 31, 1923 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 24)
  - Volume 13, Jan 1, 1924-Jul 31, 1925 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 25)
- Court Dockets, 1864-1926; 27 Volumes
  Contains: alphabetized index to prisoners; names; magistrate; prosecutor; date of commitment; offence; how discharged.
  - Volume 1, Feb 6, 1864-Sep 19, 1867 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 26)
  - Volume 2, Sep 20, 1867-Dec 17, 1870 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 27)
  - Volume 3, Dec 19, 1870-Oct 21, 1873 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 28)
  - Volume 4, Oct 21, 1873-Dec 25, 1875 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 29)
  - Volume 5, Dec 26, 1875-Aug 31, 1877 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 30)
  - Volume 6, Mar 8, 1880-Aug 12, 1882 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 31)
  - Volume 7, Oct 12, 1884-Jul 14, 1887 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 32)
  - Volume 8, Dec 22, 1888-May 1, 1890 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 33)
  - Volume 9, May 1, 1890-Sep 11, 1891 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 34)
  - Volume 10, Apr 4, 1893-Aug 11, 1894 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 35)
  - Volume 11, Aug 11, 1894-Aug 5, 1896 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 36)
  - Volume 12, Aug 5, 1896-Nov 14, 1898 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 37)
  - Volume 13, Nov 14, 1898-Jan 8, 1901 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Drawer 9, Reel 38)
  - Volume 14, Jan 9, 1901-Aug 25, 1902 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 39)
  - Volume 15, Aug 25, 1902-Apr 19, 1904 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 40)
  - Volume 16, Apr 20, 1904-Nov 30, 1905 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 41)
  - Volume 17, Jun 21, 1907-Sep 6, 1908 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 42)
  - Volume 18, Jul 1, 1911-Apr 18, 1913 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 43)
  - Volume 19, Apr 18, 1913-Oct 21, 1914 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 44)
  - Volume 20, Oct 22, 1914-Apr 15, 1916 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 45)
  - Volume 21, Apr 16, 1916-Jul 24, 1917 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 46)
  - Volume 22, Jul 25, 1917-Oct 1, 1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 47)
  - Volume 23, Oct 2, 1918-Feb 8, 1920 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 48)
  - Volume 24, Feb 9, 1920-Jul 5, 1921 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 49)
  - Volume 25, Jul 6, 1921-Oct 9, 1922 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 50)
  - Volume 26, Oct 10, 1922-Feb 29, 1924 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 51)
  - Volume 27, May 15, 1925-Jul 30, 1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 52)
- Index to Court Dockets, 1901-1925; IV.; 9 Volumes
  Alphabetized by first letter only.
  - Volume 1, Aug 25, 1902-Apr 19, 1904 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 53)
  - Volume 2, Dec 1, 1905-Jun 20, 1907 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 54)
  - Volume 3, Jun 21, 1907-Sep 7, 1908 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 55)
  - Volume 4, Jan 1, 1910-Jun 30, 1911 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 56)
  - Volume 5, Oct 22, 1914-Apr 15, 1916 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 57)
  - Volume 6, Apr 16, 1916 thru 1917 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 58)
  - Volume 7, Feb 9, 1920-Jul 5, 1921 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 59)
  - Volume 8, Oct 10, 1922-Feb 29, 1924 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 60)
  - Volume 9, Mar 1, 1924-May 14, 1925 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 61)
- Summary Docket (Summary Convictions; Summary Register), 1863-1929; V.; 11 Volumes
  Contains: prisoner name; magistrate; prosecutor; offence; days; remarks.
  - Volume 1, Dec 7, 1863-Sep 30, 1870 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 62)
  - Volume 2, Oct 1, 1870-Dec 24, 1875 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 63)
  - Volume 3, Mar 30, 1883-Feb 28, 1891 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 64)
  - Volume 4, Mar 1, 1891-Jun 24, 1897 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 65)
  - Volume 5, Jun 25, 1897-Mar 31, 1902 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 66)
  - Volume 6, Sep 1, 1905-Nov 17, 1908 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 67)
  - Volume 7, Nov 16, 1908-May 31, 1912 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 68)
  - Volume 8, Jun 1, 1912-Jan 31, 1916 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 69)
  - Volume 9, Feb 1, 1916-Jul 31, 1921 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 70)
  - Volume 10, Aug 1, 1921-Jul 10, 1925 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 71)
  - Volume 11, Jul 11, 1925-Jun 30, 1929 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 72)
- Summary of Convictions, 1907-1926; VI.; 5 Volumes
  Contains: alphabetized listing of prisoner names; code numbers; dates.
  - Volume 1, Mar 10, 1907-Jul 31, 1910 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 73)
  - Volume 2, Jul 10, 1910-May 31, 1913 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 74)
  - Volume 3, Jan 16, 1917-Sep 30, 1921 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 75)
  - Volume 4, Sep 3, 1921-Mar 31, 1924 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 76)
  - Volume 5, Apr 1, 1924-May 31, 1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 77)
- Courts: Received and Discharged, 1886-1922; VII.; 6 Volumes
  Contains: dates and names of prisoners received; dates and names of prisoners discharged.
  - Volume 1, Sep 1, 1886-Sep 15, 1891 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 78)
  - Volume 2, Feb 1, 1896-Feb 28, 1902 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 79)
  - Volume 3, Mar 1, 1902-Nov 1, 1905 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 80)
  - Volume 4, Nov 1, 1908-Apr 30, 1912 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 81)
  - Volume 5, Nov 1, 1915-Oct 31, 1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 82)
  - Volume 6, Nov 1, 1918-Feb 28, 1922 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 83)
- Daily Disposition Record, 1906-1925; VIII.; 4 Volumes
  Contains: names of prisoners discharged each day; code number; name; condition of release.
  - Volume 1, Dec 1, 1906-Dec 31, 1908 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 84)
  - Volume 2, Nov 1, 1914-Jul 23, 1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 85)
  - Volume 3, Jul 25, 1918-May 31, 1922 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 86)
  - Volume 4, Jun 1, 1922-Dec 18, 1925 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 87)
- Alphabetized List of Prisoners' and Attorneys' Names, Nov 11, 1914-Apr 25, 1921; IX.; 1 volume (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 88)
- Docket of United States Prisoners, Nov 27, 1899-Dec 30, 1926; X.; 1 volume (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 89)
  Contains: date of commitment; race; name; offence; by whom committed; term of sentence; period charged, from, to; date of discharge; by whom discharged; remarks; quarterly recapitulation. 4,799 prisoners listed.
- Convict Description Docket, Aug 30, 1920-Dec 23, 1932; XI.; 1 volume (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 90)
  Contains: register number; name; when received; age when received; color; sex; nativity; color of hair and eyes; marks and scars; height; weight; parental relations; length of school attendance; Sunday school attendance; literacy; industrial training; occupation; drinking habits; marital status; military service; date of sentence; term of sentence; number of convictions; time served; remarks. 5,344 prisoners listed.
- Discharge Description Docket, 1873-1928; XII.; 2 Volumes
  Contains: register number; name; age when discharged; color; sex; crime; date of sentence; when discharged; how discharged; whether or not detained for costs for misconduct; time served; weight; amount earned in overwork during imprisonment; intended residence; remarks.
  - Volume 1, Aug 20, 1873-Oct 8, 1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 91)
  - Volume 2, Oct 8, 1918-Nov 28, 1928 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 92)
- Quarterly Report of All Persons Committed to Allegheny County Prison, Jan 28, 1909-Jan 31, 1912; XIII.; 1 volume (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 93)
  Contains: register number; name; and how prisoner was disposed of.
- Ledger, Jan 1900-Jan 1921; XIV.; 1 volume (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 94)
- Journal (Day Book), 1902-1924; XV.; 3 Volumes
  - Volume 1, Jan 15, 1902-Dec 31, 1909 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 95)
  - Volume 2, Jan 5, 1910-Dec 31, 1915 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 96)
  - Volume 3, Jan 10, 1916-Dec 31, 1924 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 97)
- Cash Book, Jun 6, 1923-Feb 14, 1927; XVI.; 1 volume (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Reel 98)